Haemin Ryu | Curriculum Vitae

My vision is to improve human mobility experiences by designing products with analyzed data and emerging technology

to make more people access anywhere without barriers, regardless of impairments and age.

My interests rest at the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Universal Design, Extended Reality, and Accessibility.

🜐 haeminryu.com 📧 design.haemin.ryu@gmail.com 📱 +1 (260) 255-2983

Education

Mar. 2014-Feb. 2020

Dual Degree Program Scholar

Graduated Dec.2019

B. S. in Computer Science

Purdue University, Fort Wayne, IN, USA

Honors: PFW Top 50 (Annually recognizes 50 students for outstanding work and extracurricular achievements)

Graduated Feb.2020

B. E. in Computer Science

Seoul Women's University, Seoul, South Korea

Honors: Merit-based Scholar with Highest Distinction (Full-ride tuition granted for two semesters) Summa Cum Laude (3 of 71 students, in the top 1-5% of the Computer Science Major class)

Research Experience

2022 [2] Menu interfaces to Avoid Disembodiment Situations in Virtual Reality

Advisor: Dr. Beomjin Kim / Information Analytics and Visualization (IAV) Center

- Analyzed different Virtual Reality (VR) menu styles in Unity to investigate the method/design to improve the interaction between menu interfaces and users focused on user reactions to the disembodiment issue.

2020 [1] Improvement to Pix2Code using Fast.ai: Automatic Generation of GUI with a Model Classification

Advisor: Dr. Venkata Inukollu / Submitted to Student Research and Creative Endeavor Symposium 2020

- Demonstrated that automated deep learning model classification using Fast.ai can improve the accuracy and speed of the Pix2Code GUI Generation.

Selected Projects

Oct. 2021 [2] PLUR: Online Platform for Physical Education Community for Individuals with Disabilities

#Accessibility #Sports #Community

- Created a web app that uses local resources and crowdsourcing to make sports programs and facilities more accessible to individuals with disabilities.
- Developed scenarios for connecting differently abled children and young adults with verified local coaches, trainers, sports associations, and clubs to begin their journey in sports.

Aug. 2018-Apr. 2019

[1] Indoor Navigation: Improved Accessibility for People with Disabilities (Sponsor: ** PARKVIEW)

#Accessibility #DataVisualization #Navigation #Beacon #DataAnalytics

- Leveraged hospital navigation data from beacon technology focused on the patient experience to provide a more accessible hospital visit experience for patients with disabilities.
- Designed a data analytics web application to discover heavy/light usage facilities and routes at the hospital and improved mobile application navigation to assist patients.
- Built a web interface that visualizes interactive data analytics and displays employee administration management systems using Angular 7, TypeScript, and HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

Professional Experience

Jan. 2020-Present

Software Developer

Cirrus ABS Corporation (MarketSnare), Fort Wayne, IN, USA

- Delivered a local marketing web platform, MarketSnare, which meets multi-location business needs with centralized management, localization, and customization for various regions to +25 nationwide clients.
- Developed web solutions with the MarketSnare software platforms using the Microsoft ASP.NET framework, C#, XML, XSLT, JSON, HTML/CSS/JS, API integrations, Database management, and Web Server Technologies.

	Awards & Honors
Oct. 2022	ACM UIST Travel Grant [™] , Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Office of SIG Services, USD 1,338
Oct. 2021	Hack for Humanity Top 7 Finalist of 59 worldwide competitors, Arizona State University
Feb. 2021	The second secon
Feb. 2020	
Oct. 2019	·
May. 2019	
Apr. 2019	•
2018, 2019	·
2018, 2019	
Nov. 2015	
2014, 2015	
Jul. 2015	LIKELION Ideathon - Top 10 out of 110 projects with over 500 college students in Korea, LIKELION
	Presentations & Lectures
Apr. 8th, 2022	Ryu, H. (2022). UX Design for Web Developers. University of Illinois Web Conference, University of Illinois,
	Champaign, IL (Virtual). April 6–8, 2022.
Dec. 13th, 2019	Ryu, H. (2019). Journey to Conference on Automated Software Engineering. Guest Lecture for
	CS 36000 Software Engineering, Purdue University, Fort Wayne, IN. December 13, 2019.
	Panels
Dec. 7th, 2022	
Nov. 28th, 2022	
Apr. 15th, 2022	
,	
Apr. 12th, 2021	•
Nov. 20th, 2019	"A Day in their Shoes" Simulation with Panel Discussion, Purdue University, Fort Wayne, IN. Office of International Education
	Teaching Experience
	Teaching Assistant, Department of Computer Science; Purdue University Fort Wayne
Fall 2018–Fall 2019	CS 36000 Software Engineering
Summer 2019	CS 16000 Intro to Computer Science I (Java Programming)
	Tutoring, Department of Computer Science; Seoul Women's University & Purdue University Fort Wayne
Fall 2018–Spring 2019	Analytic Geometry and Calculus I & II for college students, Core Academic Skills Assessment (CASA)
Spring 2016–Fall 2016	Programming education for elementary school students, Play with Software by NAVER Connect Fdn.
	Voluntaaring & Extra Curricular
2020 2022	Volunteering & Extra Curricular
2020–2022	Student Volunteer at UIST 2020 & 2021 & 2022, CHI 2021, ICSE 2020, ACM International Conference
Aug. 2021–Mar. 2022 Aug. 2021–Oct. 2021	UX/UI Designer for Seed Fund Initiative Project, United Nations SDSN Global Youth Lead Like a Girl Challenge Project for Young Women Leaders, Go Laadli
2018–2020	Event Organizer for Global Game Jam (2020), ACM-PFW (2018-19), BIG Event: Student-led service (Spring 2018&2019),
2014–2017	Club Seoul: Korean Student Association (2018-19), New Student Orientation (Summer 2018&2019) Outreach Volunteer What? Accessibility Support, English-Korean Translation, Delivery, Mural Painting, Poster Design,
20.7. 2017	Where? Dongan Disabilities Retreat, Good Neighbors I'm your PEN, Coal Briquettes for Neighbors,
	Into Dreams and People Youth Volunteers for Philippine Disaster recovery by the Ministry of
	Gender Equality and Family of Korea and Korea Rotary Youth Association, and more

2014 Student Council for Department of Computer Science at Seoul Women's University